<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"[]>
<metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin>Government of Canada / Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada (GC/AAFC)</origin>
                <pubdate>200904</pubdate>
                <title>Land Cover for agricultural regions of Canada, circa 2000</title>
                <edition>1.4</edition>
                <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
                <pubinfo>
                    <pubplace>Canada</pubplace>
                    <publish>Government of Canada / Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada (GC/AAFC)</publish>
                </pubinfo>
                <othercit>When used for reports or other derived information, the product should be sourced as per
                    citation information.
                </othercit>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>A thematic land cover classification representative of Circa 2000 conditions for agricultural
                regions of Canada. Land cover is derived from Landsat5-TM and/or 7-ETM+ multi-spectral imagery by
                inputting imagery and ground reference training data into a Decision-Tree or Supervised image
                classification process. Object segmentation, pixel filtering, and/or post editing is applied as part of
                the image classification. Mapping is corrected to the GeoBase Data Alignment Layer. National Road
                Network (1:50,000) features and other select existing land cover products are integrated into the
                product. UTM Zone mosaics and National Topographic Series map sheet (1:250,000) tiles are generated from
                individual 30 meter resolution classified scenes. A spatial index is available indicating the Landsat
                imagery scenes and dates input in the classification.

                This product is published and compiled by Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada (AAFC), but also integrates
                products mapped by other provincial and federal agencies; with appropriate legend adaptations. This
                release includes UTM Zones 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, and 22 for corresponding
                agricultural regions in Newfoundland, Prince Edward Island, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, Quebec, Ontario,
                Manitoba, Saskatchewan, Alberta and British Columbia covering approximately 370,000,000 hectares of
                mapped area.

                Mapped classes include: Water, Exposed, Built-up, Shrubland, Wetland, Grassland, Annual Crops, Perennial
                Crops and Pasture, Coniferous, Deciduous and Mixed forests. However, emphasis is placed on accurately
                delineating agricultural classes, including: annual crops (cropland and specialty crops like vineyards
                and orchards), perennial crops (including pastures and forages), and grasslands. Detailed class
                descriptions and associated digital values are included in the metadata.
            </abstract>
            <purpose>Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada (AAFC) through the National Land and Water Information Service
                (NLWIS) has compiled land cover mapping for agricultural regions across Canada, with the goal of
                accurately classifying lands at a moderate scale that are annually cultivated (cropland), permanently
                cultivated (pasture/forages), and grasslands; as well as mapping other contextual classes (such as
                built-up or forested lands). The purpose is to provide information that can be used to support land use
                decision making and a range of other agri-environmental federal, provincial, municipal and private
                projects, applications, programs and activities. Some examples of potential applications are: land use
                decision making and monitoring, impact assessment on ecosystem services, biodiversity conservation,
                water quality assessment, evaluation of temporal trends in surface properties, estimates of rates of
                change, and causes and consequences of change. The product is to be included in a land cover coverage
                for all of Canada that is planned to be made available through GeoBase (www.geobase.ca).
            </purpose>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <rngdates>
                    <begdate>199805</begdate>
                    <enddate>200210</enddate>
                </rngdates>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>Circa 2000</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>
                    -133
                </westbc>
                <eastbc>
                    -52
                </eastbc>
                <northbc>61</northbc>
                <southbc>
                    42
                </southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>GCMD</themekt>
                <themekey>Earth Science</themekey>
                <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Land Surface</themekey>
                <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Land Surface &gt; Land Use/Land Cover</themekey>
                <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Land Surface &gt; Landscape</themekey>
                <themekey>Earth Science &gt; Land Surface &gt; Land Use/Land Cover &gt; Land Use Classes</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>none</themekt>
                <themekey>GCMD</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>CEONET</placekt>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Alberta</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; British Columbia</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Manitoba</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; New Brunswick</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Newfoundland And Labrador</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Nova Scotia</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Ontario</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Prince Edward Island</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Quebec</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada &gt; Saskatchewan</placekey>
                <placekey>Canada</placekey>
            </place>
            <place>
                <placekt>none</placekt>
                <placekey>GCMD</placekey>
                <placekey>CEONET</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 9</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 10</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 11</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 12</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 13</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 14</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 15</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 16</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 17</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 18</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 19</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 20</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 21</placekey>
                <placekey>UTM Zone 22</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Use of data is subject to the AAFC UNRESTRICTED USE LICENSE AGREEMENT:
            http://www.agr.gc.ca/nlwis/index_e.cfm?s1=data_donnees&amp;page=licen
        </accconst>
        <useconst>Use of data is subject to the AAFC UNRESTRICTED USE LICENSE AGREEMENT:
            http://www.agr.gc.ca/nlwis/index_e.cfm?s1=data_donnees&amp;page=licen
        </useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Agri-Environment Services Branch (AESB)</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Service Desk</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <address>Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada</address>
                    <city>Ottawa</city>
                    <state>Ontario</state>
                    <country>Canada</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>+01-613-759-1000</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>+01-613-759-7977</cntfax>
                <cntemail>nlwis-snite_AT_agr.gc.ca</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.6.1500</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>The classification is not without error. There are many aspects of satellite image classification
                that introduce uncertainty in the final product, for example spatial resolution and spectral mixing. The
                following indicators of product quality and thematic accuracy are calculated by Agriculture and
                Agri-Food Canada. Please also refer to the Logical Consistency Report section for additional comments on
                product quality. 1) A cross-validation measure based on training data input into each scene by scene
                classification was performed. As a result, based on 97 scenes evaluated, the overall accuracies
                estimates recorded for each scene are summarized as follows: Minimum: 72.8%, Maximum: 96.3%, Mean 86.8%.
                2) A thematic (pixel) consistency measurement of overlapping areas between classified scenes was
                performed. As a result, based on 151 overlapping cases, the percentage consistency measured between
                scenes is summarized as follows: Minimum: 72.9%, Maximum: 98.9%, Mean 92.1%. 3) An overall accuracy
                measure using independent ground reference information collected based on a stratified systematic
                sampling grid across Canada was performed. A total of 3164 sample points were collected and evaluated
                against approximately 370,000,000 hectares of mapped area. As a result, an overall thematic class
                accuracy of approximately 82% was calculated. Considering the proportion of class areas represented and
                the density of sampling, this is estimated to be within +/- 1.5% at the 95% confidence level. 4) Areas
                reported by the 2001 Census of Agriculture (Statistics Canada, 2002) are compared with common Annual
                Cropland, grassland and Perennial Crops and Pasture. Approximately 239,434,510 hectares across Canada
                are analyzed. Results for four relative comparisons between the mapped land cover areas versus the area
                reported by the Census (mapped/census*100) are as follows: a) Annual Cropland = 103.0%; b) Perennial
                Crops and Improved Pasture = 139.6%; c) Unimproved Pasture (Grassland) = 76.8% (Note: unimproved pasture
                is not always associated with grassland, and grasslands may not be used as unimproved pasture); d)
                Perennial Crops, Improved Pasture and Unimproved Pasture (Grassland) combined = 105.0%.
            </attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>Please note the following: 1) It is not feasible to obtain cloud free imagery within a single growing
            season over a large area. As such, the classification product is based on a set of images that range within
            the 1998-2003 time period. This may produce some temporal inconsistencies across the product. The presence
            of cloud in Landsat images may limit the completeness of classes within specific regions of the product. 2)
            Comparison with National Topographic Database 1:50,000 features indicate some miss-representation of wetland
            and water features. This may be due to the use of early spring imagery (high water level) in the
            classification or error introduced by the classification process. Confusion between or poor separation of
            forested and wetland and/or shrubland covers was observed in the classification results in landscapes where
            such covers typically intermix. 3) Small (less than 0.4 ha) features may be omitted from the classification,
            due to segmentation and filtering. 4) Some confusion between Cropland and Grassland features has been
            observed (specifically, along rivers and along roadways). 5) The classification process is designed to
            classify barren fields as annual cropland when tilled soils in the spring image become green with vegetation
            in the summer image. Tilled fields are occasionally miss-classified as exposed. 6) When possible, areas
            under cloud, cloud shadows and mountain shadows were interpreted manually. 7) Agricultural classes were
            often confused under cloud and cloud shadow cover.
        </logic>
        <complete>UTM Zones include 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, and 22 for corresponding
            agricultural regions in Newfoundland, Prince Edward Island, Nova Scotia, New Brunswick, Quebec, Ontario,
            Manitoba, Saskatchewan, Alberta and British Columbia. Mapped areas are based on Landsat scene coverage of
            corresponding agricultural regions in Canada.
        </complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>This digital geo-spatial product is corrected to within 1 pixel of the Geobase Data Alignment
                    Layer (GDAL) standard (www.geobase.ca). The GDAL provides reference ground control points and
                    features for ortho-correction of Landsat imagery.
                </horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Canada Centre for Remote Sensing</origin>
                        <title>Landsat Imagery</title>
                        <othercit>LANDSAT Data received by Canada Centre for Remote Sensing (CCRS) under agreement with
                            U.S. Geological Survey. Processed &amp; distributed by MDA Geospatial Services Inc.
                            (http://gs.mdacorporation.com/) under agreement with CCRS.
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>GeoBase®</origin>
                        <pubdate>2003</pubdate>
                        <title>Landsat 7 Orthorectified Imagery over Canada</title>
                        <othercit>GeoBase® Unrestricted Licence Agreement http://www.geobase.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>GeoBase®</origin>
                        <title>Canadian Digital Elevation Data</title>
                        <othercit>GeoBase® Unrestricted Licence Agreement http://www.geobase.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>GeoBase®</origin>
                        <pubdate>2003</pubdate>
                        <title>National Road Network 2.0</title>
                        <othercit>GeoBase® Unrestricted Licence Agreement http://www.geobase.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>GeoBase®</origin>
                        <pubdate>2004</pubdate>
                        <title>Control Points for Landsat 7 Imagery 1.0</title>
                        <othercit>GeoBase® Unrestricted Licence Agreement http://www.geobase.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>GeoBase®</origin>
                        <pubdate>2008</pubdate>
                        <title>GeoBase Orthoimage 2005-2010</title>
                        <othercit>GeoBase® Unrestricted Licence Agreement http://www.geobase.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada and Statistics Canada</origin>
                        <pubdate>2007</pubdate>
                        <title>2001 Interpolated Census of Agriculture</title>
                        <othercit>Interpolated Census of Agriculture: Adapted from Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada and
                            Statistics Canada, customized tabulations, Census of Agriculture CGC Base 1996, 2001, Census
                            of Agriculture Regular Base 1971, 1976, 1981, 1986, 1991. Licensed to AAFC on February 8,
                            2007.
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Agricultural Financial Services Corporation</origin>
                        <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
                        <title>Ground Truth/Reference Data, 2007</title>
                        <othercit>http://www.afsc.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Agricultural Financial Services Corporation</origin>
                        <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
                        <title>Crop Insurance Information, 1997-2003</title>
                        <othercit>http://www.afsc.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Iunctus Geomatics Corp, Lethbridge, Alberta, Canada</origin>
                        <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
                        <title>SPOT Imagery 2.5 meters of 2005-06</title>
                        <othercit>Licensed by Iunctus Geomatics Corp, Lethbridge, Alberta, Canada. Copyright 2006 CNES.
                            http://www.terraengine.com
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Natural Resources Canada, Canadian Forest Service, Northern Forestry Centre</origin>
                        <pubdate>2006</pubdate>
                        <title>Earth Observation for Sustainable Development of Forests (EOSD), Land Cover, Circa 2000
                        </title>
                        <othercit>EOSD data and products are freely available to the public.
                            http://www.pfc.forestry.ca/eosd
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Government of Canada, Natural Resources Canada, Earth Sciences Sector, Geomatics Canada,
                            Centre for Topographic Information
                        </origin>
                        <title>National Topographic Data Base (NTDB)</title>
                        <othercit>© Her Majesty the Queen in Right of Canada, Department of Natural Resources. All
                            rights reserved. http://www.cits.rncan.gc.ca
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Government of Canada, Natural Resources Canada, Earth Sciences Sector, Geomatics Canada,
                            Centre for Topographic Information
                        </origin>
                        <title>CanMatrix</title>
                        <othercit>© Her Majesty the Queen in Right of Canada, Department of Natural Resources. All
                            rights reserved. http://www.cits.rncan.gc.ca
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Government of Canada, Natural Resources Canada, Earth Sciences Sector, Geomatics Canada,
                            Centre for Topographic Information
                        </origin>
                        <title>CanImage</title>
                        <othercit>© Her Majesty the Queen in Right of Canada, Department of Natural Resources. All
                            rights reserved. http://www.cits.rncan.gc.ca
                        </othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Manitoba Conservation, Manitoba Remote Sensing Centre</origin>
                        <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
                        <title>LANDSAT-based Land Use/Land Cover (2000) for the Agro-region of Manitoba</title>
                        <othercit>http://www.gov.mb.ca/conservation/geomatics</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Consortium of federal and provincial agencies, including: EC, Faune Québec, DUC, MRNFP,
                            MAPAQ, AAFC, FAQ
                        </origin>
                        <pubdate>unpublished material</pubdate>
                        <title>Occupation du sol à partir des images classifiées Landsat-7, Sud du Québec, 1999-2003
                        </title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin>Ontario Ministry of Natural Resources</origin>
                        <title>Ontario Land Cover Data Base 2000</title>
                        <othercit>www.mnr.gov.on.ca</othercit>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>This product is compiled and published by Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada (AAFC). The product
                    integrates select products mapped by other provincial and federal agencies; with appropriate legend
                    adaptations. The following summaries the general classification processes and aspects of the map
                    compilation; including: 1) data inputs, 2) image pre-processing, 3) classification, 4) product
                    integration, 5) post-processing, 6) mosaic, 7) quality assurance measures and 8) accuracy
                    components. For further information, please contact Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada. 1) Data inputs
                    include: 1A) Landsat5 TM or Landsat7 ETM+ satellite imagery. One to three image dates within the
                    growing season were used including imagery ranging from 1998-2003. Priority was given to using
                    imagery closest to year 2000. Landsat images from different years may be used within a scene. More
                    than one image is preferred in order to accurately separate annual crops from perennial crops and
                    pasture, as the classes have varying spectral characteristics over the growing season. 1B) Reference
                    data used to train the classifier was collected or interpreted with reference to a variety of
                    sources such as crop insurance databases, air photos, and/or satellite imagery (SPOT, IKONOS,
                    Quickbird), visual interpretation of Landsat images, other topographic map references, or through
                    field collection where possible. 1C) Ancillary data such as DEM, DEM-derived products (slope,
                    aspect) and soils information may be used as appropriate. 2) Pre-Processing includes: 2A)
                    Ortho-rectification of images using a standard 3D multi-sensor physical model that positionally
                    corrected images to the GeoBase Data Alignment Layer (www.geobase.ca). 2B) Atmospheric correction
                    using the ATCOR algorithm; however, in most cases, Landsat images were not atmospherically corrected
                    except where obvious heterogeneous conditions occur. 2C) A Tasseled Cap (TC) transformation (for
                    scenes classified using a decision tree classifier) that converts bands 1 to 5 and 7 of image pairs
                    into three channels (brightness, greenness, wetness). 2D) Creation of masks to identify areas
                    contaminated with cloud and shadow, or to mask other land cover types are created where required.
                    2E) Computation of an intra-pixel texture band based on the local variance in an adaptively placed 3
                    by 3 window of the green band on the mid-season image. 3) AAFC Classification: A Decision Tree (DT)
                    classifier was principally implemented by AAFC using software that generates a set of decision rules
                    defined by combinations of features and a set of linear discriminate functions that are applied to
                    each training node. The training sites, tassel cap and texture channels and other ancillary data for
                    each Landsat scene were input into See5 software to produce 12 classes. A two-level hierarchical
                    classification scheme is implemented in the DT process that allows the landscape to be divided into
                    general classes within which more detailed classes can be discriminated. The two-level
                    classification assists the delineation of sub-classes within agricultural and forest areas. AAFC
                    developed custom processes, scripts and software to perform the classification. 4) Product
                    Integration: Select existing products were integrated by adapting legends using defined cross-walk
                    tables and using defined mosaic seam lines or integration procedures. This included the following
                    four products: 4A) The Earth Observation for Sustainable Development of Forests (EOSD) Land Cover,
                    circa 2000 published by Natural Resources Canada, Canadian Forest Service was produced using a
                    supervised classification approach. 4B) The Manitoba Remote Sensing Centre (MRSC) used image
                    processing software to map 17 classes for agricultural regions of Manitoba. Classification was based
                    on landsat imagery using a supervised classification approach. The original 17 classes are converted
                    by AAFC to 10 comparable classes. 4C) The Saint-Lawrence Valley in Quebec was classified using
                    Landsat ETM and TM imagery and a supervised classification methodology. The original 25 classes were
                    converted by AAFC to 10 comparable classes. 4D) The Ontario Land Cover Data Base 2000 was performed
                    using a supervised classification method on Landsat data. 5) Filtering and post editing: In order to
                    remove mis-classified or noisy pixels from the classification two approaches were used: 5A) An
                    object-oriented filter approach that best accommodates landscape physical properties. For this,
                    segment objects used for filtering are generated using multi-temporal Tasseled Cap bands using
                    Definiens software. A majority filter is applied to the DT generated per-pixel classification using
                    the resulting segmented objects. This technique was primarily used in prairie regions of Canada were
                    it fit the more homogeneous landscape 5B) In other more heterogeneous landscapes, a SIEVE filter was
                    applied to the classification. Finally, manual editing of pixel values was applied as needed to
                    correct obvious identified classification errors. 6) Mosaic: Two approaches were used to mosaic
                    individual classified scenes together. 6A) An approach based on the object-based filtered segments
                    are input to an ArcGIS model that prioritises scenes based on consistency results and case files.
                    Selected segments are then converted to raster format and a mosaic is generated. This process
                    optimizes final product accuracy and minimizes visual inconsistencies by generating cut features
                    along segmented object edges. 6B) Cut lines are manually created through areas with high levels of
                    consistency between scenes. This minimizes visual inconsistencies in the mosaic. In all regions,
                    raster sub-set of National Road Network (1:50,000) features were burned or integrated into the
                    classification to preserve features lost through segmentation or filtering. 7)Quality
                    assurance/controls include: 7A) An initial cross-validation accuracy calculation of scenes
                    classified by AAFC based on the centroids of the training site polygons. The goal of this step is
                    not to evaluate absolute accuracy, but to ensure for each scene that sufficient training data were
                    collected, as well as, ensure reasonable class representation and consistency of interpretation of
                    classes. 7B) Qualitative visual evaluation of the thematic classification by an independent
                    interpreter for each completed scene. Although this can be subjective, reference to ancillary data
                    and source imagery are used. If significant errors are found, images are reclassified or post
                    editing is performed. 7C) A consistency analysis of overlapping classified scenes to identify
                    thematic differences between scenes was performed. This helped determine which scene should be given
                    priority in the mosaic process, and potentially identify if re-classification or post-editing is
                    required. High consistency between scenes provides a level of confidence in the classification. 7D)
                    Areas reported by the 2001 Census of Agriculture (Statistics Canada, 2002) are compared with common
                    classified agricultural land areas as validation that resulting classification areas are reasonable.
                    8) Absolute accuracy assessment includes: Collection of independent reference data base on a
                    stratified systematic sampling grid. The density of points is defined by determining the precision
                    desired and by considering spatial variability of land cover classes. A confidence level of 95% or
                    greater is targeted in the selection of the sampling density. High resolution imagery are primarily
                    used by interpreters to populate the ground reference databases. Error matrix analysis is used to
                    calculate overall accuracy statistics. Preliminary results are reported in the Attribute Accuracy
                    Report of the metadata.
                </procdesc>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>Agri-Environment Services Branch (AESB)</cntorg>
                            <cntper>Service Desk</cntper>
                        </cntorgp>
                        <cntaddr>
                            <address>Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada</address>
                            <city>Ottawa</city>
                            <state>Ontario</state>
                            <country>Canada</country>
                        </cntaddr>
                        <cntvoice>+01-613-759-1000</cntvoice>
                        <cntfax>+01-613-759-7977</cntfax>
                        <cntemail>nlwis-snite_AT_agr.gc.ca</cntemail>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spref>
        <horizsys>
            <planar>
                <gridsys>
                    <gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM)</gridsysn>
                    <utm></utm>
                </gridsys>
                <planci>
                    <plance>row and column</plance>
                    <coordrep>
                        <absres>30.000000</absres>
                        <ordres>30.000000</ordres>
                    </coordrep>
                    <plandu>meters</plandu>
                </planci>
            </planar>
            <geodetic>
                <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
                <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
                <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
                <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
            </geodetic>
        </horizsys>
    </spref>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp></enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Value</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Digital values (codes) associated with the land cover classification product.</attrdef>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <overview>
            <eaover>Entity and Attribute Overview: The following is a list of classes and digital values associated with
                the classification product: Code: 0 Title: No Data Description: No Data Comments: RGB: 0 0 0 Code: 10
                Title: Unclassified Description: Areas unclassified due to cloud, shadow or other image quality factors.
                Comments: RGB: 51 51 51 Code: 20 Title: Water Description: Water bodies (lakes, reservoirs, rivers,
                streams, salt water, etc.) Comments: RGB: 51 51 255 Code: 30 Title: Exposed Land Description:
                Predominately non-vegetated and non-developed. Includes: exposed lands, bare soil, snow, glacier, rock,
                sediments, burned areas, rubble, mines, other naturally occurring non-vegetated surfaces. Comments:
                Mines or similar human activity may be mapped by this class, or may be mapped by the developed class.
                Excludes fallow agriculture. RGB: 153 102 102 Code: 34 Title: Built-up Description: Land predominantly
                built-up or developed; including vegetation associated with these cover conditions. This may include
                road surfaces, railway surfaces, buildings and paved surfaces, urban areas, parks, industrial sites,
                mine structures and farmsteads. May also include golf courses and ski hills. Comments: RGB: 204 102 153
                Code: 50 Title: Shrubland Description: Predominantly woody vegetation of relatively low height
                (generally +/-2 meters). Comments: May include grass or grassland wetlands with woody vegetation,
                regenerating forest. RGB: 255 255 0 Code: 80 Title: Wetland Description: Land with a water table
                near/at/above soil surface for enough time to promote wetland or aquatic processes (semi-permanent or
                permanent wetland vegetation, including fens, bogs, swamps, sloughs, marshes etc). Comments: This class
                is mapped based on cover properties corresponding with image date(s) conditions. RGB: 153 51 153 Code:
                110 Title: Grassland, Native Grass Description: Predominantly native grasses and other herbaceous
                vegetation, may include some shrubland cover. Land used for range or native unimproved pasture may
                appear in this class. Comments: Alpine meadows fall into this class. RGB: 204 204 0 Code: 120 Title:
                Cultivated Agricultural Land Description: Agricultural land, including annual and perennial crops; and
                would exclude grassland. Comments: This class is mapped when the distinction of sub-agricultural covers
                (classes 121-122) is not possible. RGB: 204 102 0 Code: 121 Title: Annual Cropland Description: Annually
                cultivated cropland and woody perennial crops. Includes annual field crops, vegetables, summer fallow,
                orchards and vineyards. Comments: Classification process primarily detects and delineates lands that
                change from bare cover to green/vegetated cover during the growing season. RGB: 255 153 51 Code: 122
                Title: Perennial Cropland and Pasture Description: Periodically cultivated cropland. Includes tame
                grasses and other perennial crops such as alfalfa and clover grown alone or as mixtures for hay, pasture
                or seed. Comments: Fall seeded crops such as winter wheat may be erroneously identified in this class.
                Grassland and shrubland may be delineated within in this class. RGB: 255 204 51 Code: 200 Title: Forest/
                Trees Description: Predominantly forested or treed areas. Comments: This class is mapped only if the
                distinction of sub-forest covers (classes 210, 220, 230) is not possible. RGB: 0 153 0 Code: 210 Title:
                Coniferous Forest Description: Predominantly coniferous forests or treed areas. May include mixed
                forests and shrubland areas. Comments: RGB: 0 102 0 Code: 220 Title: Deciduous Forest Description:
                Predominantly broadleaf/deciduous forests or treed areas. May include mixed forests and shrubland areas.
                Comments: RGB: 0 204 0 Code: 230 Title: Mixed Forest Description: Mixed coniferous and
                broadleaf/deciduous forests or treed areas. Comments: RGB: 204 153 0
            </eaover>
        </overview>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo></digtinfo>
            </digform>
        </stdorder>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>